## Baldeep Kaur | baldeep.kaur23@rutgers.edu Whiteland, IN | (908) 305-0234

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Highly motivated Computer Science major with strong intercultural and diversity networks. 6 years of working experience in C++, Java, C#(familiar), JavaScript, TypeScript, Python(familiar), and SQL. Seeking an opportunity that will allow me to advance my skills in this field

#### **Expertise**

6 years of working experience with Web Development (**Microservices**, Restful APIs, Spring Framework, Eureka, NodeJS, ReactJS) and DevOps systems (**Jenkins**, **SonarQube**, **Docker**).

- Experience with Test Driven Development (TDD)
- Backend databases (MongoDB, MS SQL, Oracle)
- Proficient with container systems like **Docker** and container orchestration like EC2 Container service and **Kubernetes**.
- Strong In Frontend Technology: ReactJS, Bootstrap
- Strong In Backend Frameworks: Spring Framework, Spring Boot,
   NodeJS
- Experience working with cloud services: Microsoft Azure, AWS,
   Google Cloud.
- Experience working with deployment tools: Heroku, Jenkins
- Expertise in database querying and analytics: Hibernate,
   MongoDB, MySQL
- Experience in code management services: **GitHub, GitLab**
- Experience in CI/CD Tools: **Jenkins**

Skills

**Programming Languages:** C++, Java, C#(familiar), JavaScript, TypeScript, Python(familiar), SQL

**Frameworks and tools:** Java Core, Spring Boot, Java EE, NodeJS, ExpressJS, AngularJS, jQuery, <u>ASP.NET</u>, Subversion, Git, MongoDB, Amazon Web Services (EC2, Route 53), Xcode, Visual Studio

**Operating Systems:** macOS, Windows, Linux/Unix

#### **Work Experience**

SCHNEIDER NATIONAL, Green Bay, WI April 2019 – Present

(IBM Contractor)

Java Full Stack Developer

#### **RESPONSIBILITES**

- Performed extreme programming and Test Driven Development (TDD)
- Created new applications with microservices architecture using
   Restful APIs, Spring Boot Core Java, Oracle, and Gradle.
- Weekly sprints using agile development methodologies and attending daily scrum meetings.
- Used SonarQube to check and increase code coverage.
- Created models using Lombok, created validations and built tests around them.
- Created SQL queries to add new tables and columns to existing database.
- Interacted with multiple client's APIs to fetch loads.
- Used GitHub to commit and push code on daily basis.
- Scheduled cronjobs in Kubernetes.
- Created UI for API data presentation using ReactJS.
- Gave tutorials to team mates on fundamentals of ReactJS.
- Enhanced and debugged existing ReactJS project.

**Technologies/Environment:** Spring Boot, Restful webservices using microservices architecture, Gradle, Lombok, Hibernate, HTML, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Oracle SQL Server, GIT, GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Kubernetes, Jenkins, SonarQube.

# UMB BANK, Kansas City, MO Aug 2017 – March 2019 Java Full Stack/NodeJS Developer

#### **RESPONSIBILITES**

- Enhanced web application using Java, JSTL, Spring, Hibernate.
- Worked on migrating existing applications into microservices architecture using Rest APIs, spring boot, and AWS.
- Developed Nodejs RESTful services. ReactJS frontend web application development.
- Used tools like VScode, Robo Mongo, Win Merge, Putty, FileZilla, and Rally during the development lifecycle.
- Used Jenkins as a webhook with GitHub as continuous integration and continuous development tool.
- Experience in dock raising the image in virtual Machine.
- Used underscore.js for useful functional programming helpers without extending any built-in objects.
- Used GitHub for version control.
- Developed UI using JSTL, Javascript, CSS HTML, AJAX

**Technologies/Environment:** Spring Boot, Jenkins, Eureka, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Mongo DB, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, SQL server, MySQL, GIT.

JOHN DEERE, Chicago, IL May 2016 – July 2017

### Java Developer

#### **RESPONSIBILITES**

- Developed business components using core java concepts and classes like Inheritance, Polymorphism, Collections etc.
- Used Spring framework that handles application logic and makes calls to business objects and services mainly SOAP Web services.
- Implemented DAO for data access using HIBERNATE.

- Used SVN as version control to check in the code, created branches, and tagged the code in SVN.
- Code quality check using PMD, Code coverage checks using SONAR.
- Compiled complex SQL queries required to fetch the data from Oracle data source.
- Created microservices and REST services using Spring Boot.

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

- Python for Data Visualization, Python, Linux, Fortran, Ruby, Cyber Security,
   Microeconomics, Calculus 3
- Certified in Advanced Google Analytics
- Certified in Advanced Google Data Studios

#### **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University - Newark, NJ

- Major: Computer Science
- The graduation year is May 2022
- Bachelor of Arts